About

Brenna Briles is a 22 year old graduating senior at the University of Texas at Austin. She was born in College Station, Texas and moved to Austin for college. She is pursuing a Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology with minors in Sociology and Women and Gender Studies. After graduation, she will be attending medical school in the fall of 2020. She will be the first person in her family to earn a professional degree and to become a physician. Brenna loves working with children and had the opportunity to teach children about the environment as an animal handler. During her undergraduate experience, she participated in clinical research on pediatric traumatic brain injury, was a Child Life volunteer at Dell Children's Medical Center, and volunteered at the Central Texas Food Bank. Serving as a Child Life volunteer was her favorite activity since she had the opportunity to relieve some of the stress of living in a hospital for children with chronic illnesses. In her free time, she enjoys hiking, swimming, and seeing the natural sites abundant in Austin.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin Austin, Texas Graduating Fall 2019

The University of Texas at Arlington Arlington, Texas Fall 2016-Spring 2017

A&M Consolidated High School College Station, Texas Graduated May 2016

Work Experience

Allergies and Asthma Clinic June 2019-Present Medical Assistant

- · Administered immunotherapy injections and allergy skin tests
- Corresponded with insurance companies to confirm benefits
- Monitored patients for allergic reactions

Tiny Tails to You

April 2018 – May 2019

Animal Handler and Trainer

- Supervised and ensured safety over 13 animals and 8 children per rotation
- Provided animal education to children and adults
- Trained new employees on animal safety and handling through shadowing at events

Science Mill June 2018 - August 2018 STEM Camp Educator

- Instructed and engaged with 30 children per week in science-oriented activities
- Encouraged creativity and imagination through hands-on experiments
- Provided a free STEM summer camp for underfunded schools
- · Organized, restocked, and maintained inventory of camp materials

Activities and Interests

Osier Laboratory
April 2018 – Present
Clinical Researcher

- Volunteered at least 5 hours per week
- Consented patients into Traumatic Brain Injury study according to IRB informed consent protocol
- Utilized the Electronic Health Record to identify research participants
- Completed HIPAA and good clinical practice trainings

Dell Children's Medical Center

August 2017 – Present

Child Life and Emergency Department Volunteer

- Volunteered at least four hours per week
- · Collaborated with clinical staff regarding patient care
- Assisted in patient check-in
- Visited at least 10 patient rooms per shift to offer toys and therapeutic play to patients

Central Texas Food Bank

January 2019 - Present

Warehouse Volunteer

- Volunteered at least 2 hours per week
- Packaged food for distribution in central Texas
- Worked cooperatively with volunteers to prepare 4,000 meals per 2 hours

Inter-Cooperative Council Austin

January 2018 - December 2018

Elected Board Representative

- Attended board meetings twice a month
- Approved budgets and policies
- Collaborated with 15 peer board members to provide organizational oversight

Skills

- Electronic medical record (EMR) systems: screened electronic health records to identify and enroll
 patients with traumatic brain injury
- RStudio: proficient in ggplot and dplyr
- Customer service: recieved excellent reviews from customers at a small animal petting zoo

Honors and Achievements

College Scholar
May 2019
The University of Texas at Austin

• Academic award recieved for placement in the top 20% of class based on GPA

Contact

brennabriles@gmail.com (mailto:brennabriles@gmail.com)